Kyle Tomanelli

Astoria, NY 11103 | 347-263-4612 | KyleTomanelli@gmail.com | Portfolio | Github | Blog | LinkedIn

Full Stack Web Developer

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming as well as a background in Level 2/3 IT support. Currently volunteering on open source community driven production applications/bots designed to facilitate requests for non-emergency help as well as dispatch of volunteers who are nearby and able to assist during COVID-19. Possess strong skills in troubleshooting and problem solving that help resolve issues in a timely manner and meet deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javscript, React, NodeJs, Java, HTML/CSS, Git, Wordpress, AWS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Cisco Routing/Switching(CCNA), TCP/IP, VLANs, Firewalls, NAT, DHCP, EIGRP, OSPF, BGP, Spanning Tree, WAN

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ShapeStudio - Github: Frontend | Backend | Demo

An in-browser 3D Modeler that allows users to build and edit their 3D models. Built with React/ThreeJS frontend and Rails backend.

- Make use of React-Three-Fiber to allow ThreeJS to work properly in React components.
- Build UI for interacting with the ThreeJS canvas.
- Implement save and load features allowing users to save their work and come back to it.

Flatflix - Github: Frontend | Backend | Demo

A netflix clone, built with React frontend and Rails backend, which allows users to sign in and watch trailers of their favorite movies.

- Use JWT functionality to enable authentication for users so they can stay signed when coming back to the site.
- Use CSS Flexbox and other CSS functionality to neatly arrange React components and slightly grow in size when the user hovers over them.

Flatiron Tetris - Github: Frontend | Backend | Demo

A tetris game built with vanilla Javascript and Rails backend

- Design front end functionality to enable tetris pieces, randomly generated from backend, to appear on the grid, and fall into place
- Use event listeners to allow users to move as well as rotate their pieces on the game board.

EXPERIENCE

Astoria Digital
Volunteer Developer
Astoria, NY
03/2020 - Current

- Build Slack bot that notifies volunteer dispatchers of incoming requests for non-emergency help and provides them with contact information of volunteers who are nearby and able to provide assistance.
- Use Slack's Block Kit functionality to build interactive in-message form on each notification to flag requests for follow-up
- Build NodeJs backend of Volunteer web portal which allows volunteers to update their information.

Revel Brooklyn, NY IT Administrator 02/2020 - 03/2020

- Manage onboarding/offboarding of employees by creating/disabling accounts.
- Configure and manage new hardware via Microsoft Intune and JAMF.

Pathway Systems Design

Amityville, NY

IT Field Technician

08/2015 - 02/2020

- Provide technical & IT support for healthcare facilities & providers including NYU-Langone & Kingsbrook Jewish Medical Center
- Assist networking team with deployment and configuration of networking hardware such as Cisco Switches and Palo Alto firewall

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program
Hunter College
BA Computer Science

City, State 04/ 2020 - 07/2020 New York, NY Currently Attending